Ghazi Zabalawi

Software Developer

Contact

E-mail

ghazi-z3balawi@outlook.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/

ghazi-zabalawi-4241682

Website

https://www.ghazidev.com/

Skills

React.js

Django

Nextjs

HTML

CSS SOL

Teamwork

Communication

Leadership

Critical Thinking

My name is Ghazi, I am currently studying Bachelor of Software Engineering (Honors) at Auckland University of Technology, I am a passionate full-stack web developer, I have expertise in Reactjs, Nextjs, Django, and html and css. I am focused on developing blogs and articles based websites, and making to-do lists.

Education

2020-03 -	Bachelor of Engineering (Honors): Software
2023-12	Engineering
	Auckland University of Technology - Auckland
2017-09 -	High School Diploma
2018-08	High School - Jordan

Work History

2022-03 - **Produce Assistant**

Current Countdown, Mount Eden, AUK

- Pleasantly greeted customers and provided prompt and courteous service.
- Used dollies and pallet jacks to unload and organize merchandise from delivery trucks.
- Assisted customers with price checking fruits and vegetables and finding requested items in department.
- Inspected floor displays, noted missing items, and immediately replenished merchandise.

2020-12 - **Retail Assistant**

2021-12 Red Cross, Grafton, Auckland

- Worked as a volunteer, helped other volunteers whenever in need
- Greeted customers, helped locate merchandise, and suggested suitable options.
- Worked closely with shift manager to solve problems and handle customer concerns.
- Used POS system to process sales, returns, online orders, and gift card activations.
- Replenished sales floor merchandise and organized shelves, racks, and bins for optimal appearance.

2020-07 - Web Developer

2020-10

United Nation-ESCWA, Amman, Jordan

• Coded am SME (Small-Medium Enterprise) Toolkit website using

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript for frontend, and Drupal for backend with fully fledged team
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Developed user-friendly web forms with validation and error handling.
- Conceived and built optimized landing pages in HTML and CSS for integration and cross-browser compatibility.

Projects

Software Practice Empirical Evidence Database- (MERN Stack)

Link: https://github.com/cindychen042/Ass1B

- Led a team of 3 in developing a web app called SPEED, a searchable database of evidence about software engineering practices using the MERN technology stack
- Spearheaded the project by defining the product scope and prioritizing features in collaboration with the product owner, with a focus on supporting evidence-based decision making for software engineering practitioner
- Designed the SPEED app to enable users to easily search for and access empirical research on different software engineering practices, using a user-friendly interface and a standardized submission form for article suggestions.
- Successfully delivered the MVP of SPEED within the project timeline, showcasing strong leadership, communication, and problem-solving skills.

Article Based Website - (Next, React, Django, Postgres SQL, Nginx, Cloudflare)

Link: https://www.globeofarticles.com/

- Implemented a comprehensive user authentication system using session tokens.
- The website allows users to create articles with tags, comment on articles, and like articles.
- Each user has a profile page that displays their articles and the articles they have liked.
- Deployed the website on Nginx web server, leveraging Next.js for server-side rendering.
- Demonstrated proficiency in full-stack web development, including database management, backend development, frontend design, and deployment.